<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-11-04T15:59:38+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><entry><title type="html">An Evaluation of Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) Attacks in IoT Networks</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/11/04/mastersproject.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Evaluation of Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) Attacks in IoT Networks" /><published>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2019-11-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/11/04/mastersproject</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/11/04/mastersproject.html">&lt;p&gt;Hackers who engage in Distributed Denial of Service attacks (DDoS) use multiple systems to flood a network with traffic such as to restrict or shutdown normal network operation. &lt;!-- more --&gt;The result is usually limited or denied access to various resources such as servers, IoT devices networks and applications. Full featured operating Systems (OS) have various tools and resources at their disposal in combating these types of attacks. However, in the IoT world these resources are often limited or not even available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project will use open source software tools to evaluate IoT operating systems, networks and devices to gain an understanding as to how susceptible IoT networks are to various types of botnet attacks. It will then make informed recommendations on detection and mitigation solutions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">Hackers who engage in Distributed Denial of Service attacks (DDoS) use multiple systems to flood a network with traffic such as to restrict or shutdown normal network operation.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EE514 - Image Processing and Analysis</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE453.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EE514 - Image Processing and Analysis" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE453</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE453.html">&lt;p&gt;Most people are familiar with the concept of processing an image to improve its quality or the use of image analysis software tools to make basic measurements; but what are the ideas behind such solutions and why is knowledge of these concepts important in developing successful computer vision applications? 
 &lt;!-- more --&gt;
 These modules will answer these questions by focusing on both the theoretical, mathematical and practical issues associated with a wide range of traditional computer vision solutions. Such solutions relate to the fields of image processing and analysis, industrial/machine vision, video data processing, biomedical engineering, imaging science, sensor technology, multimedia and enhanced reality systems. ee425 and ee453 will concentrate on developing the fundamentals necessary to design, develop and understand a wide range of basic imaging processing (image to image), image analysis (image to feature), image classification (feature to decision), performance characterisation (data to quantitative performance indicators) and computer vision (image to interpretation) solutions. All solutions have limitations and a key element of this module is to focus on how to approach the design, testing and evaluation of successful computer vision applications within an engineering framework. This module will make extensive use of an image analysis development environment to reinforce all the issues covers during the lectures. Please refer to the modules summary syllabus for additional detail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the common elements associated with ee425, ee453 will contain more advanced (PLUS) image processing &amp;amp; analysis topics. The focus of this element of the module will be on developing practical engineering solutions. This module will require basic programming skills. We will develop solutions within Matlab development environment. Specifically we will use the VSG IPA toolbox (our free MATLAB compatible image processing and analysis toolbox) along with the Matlab Image Processing Toolbox.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Masters" /><summary type="html">Most people are familiar with the concept of processing an image to improve its quality or the use of image analysis software tools to make basic measurements; but what are the ideas behind such solutions and why is knowledge of these concepts important in developing successful computer vision applications?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EE500 - Network Performance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE500.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EE500 - Network Performance" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE500</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE500.html">&lt;p&gt;EE500 module introduces the students to advanced network performance concepts with focus on performance issues. 
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
The students will be reminded of the OSI and the TCP/IP models. They will be introduced to Quality of Service and Network Performance metrics as well as to Quality of Experience and Quality of Perception as metrics to assess the quality of data delivery. Various wired and wireless protocols will be introduced and their performance-related characteristics will, be discussed. These protocols will be presented at different layers of the OSI stack. At Datalink Layer WiFi (IEEE 802.11 family), WiMax (IEEE 802.16 family) and BlueTooth/UWB (IEEE 802.15) are briefly introduced before details are given about QoS-aware protocols or QoS solutions for IEEE 802.11e, IEEE 802.16e and IEEE 802.15.3, IEEE 802.15.4, UMTS. At network layer we will place emphasis on IPv4 vs IPv6, whereas at Transport Layer novel protocols such as DCCP, SCTP and others will be presented along with more established ones such as RTP and RTCP. At the Application Layer, multimedia and gaming applications will be discussed in details in the context of real-time content delivery, but other application types will also be presented. Adaptive and non-adaptive content delivery solutions will be presented along with significant issues such as end-user perceived quality. Novel performance-related issues such as mobility, power consumption and security will be presented..&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Masters" /><summary type="html">EE500 module introduces the students to advanced network performance concepts with focus on performance issues.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EE514 - Data Analytics and Machine Learning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE514.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EE514 - Data Analytics and Machine Learning" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE514</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE514.html">&lt;p&gt;This module will provide students with fundamental and advanced skills required for data analytics, including: data management, processing, summarization, and predictive analytics.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
It is focused on providing students with a strong theoretical foundation, along with the ability to make practical use of the advanced techniques in the field. The Python programming language will be used for demonstrating the use of various techniques throughout the module, giving students practical tools for solving relatively sophisticated and broadly-defined real world problems in a well-established and widely-used programming environment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Masters" /><summary type="html">This module will provide students with fundamental and advanced skills required for data analytics, including: data management, processing, summarization, and predictive analytics.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EE515 - Real Time Digital Signal Processing</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE515.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EE515 - Real Time Digital Signal Processing" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE515</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/masters/2019/10/08/EE515.html">&lt;p&gt;This module will provide students with the knowledge, skills and competencies in the area of high-speed DSP.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;It is focused on providing students with not only a strong theoretical foundation, but also the ability to make practical use of modern DSP approaches.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Masters" /><summary type="html">This module will provide students with the knowledge, skills and competencies in the area of high-speed DSP.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Streaming Audio Server with Listener-Tracking Embedded Clients (Final Year Project)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/10/08/finalyearproject.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Streaming Audio Server with Listener-Tracking Embedded Clients (Final Year Project)" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/10/08/finalyearproject</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/2019/10/08/finalyearproject.html">&lt;p&gt;The aim of this project was to implement an audio server solution
which could stream high quality audio across the network to a number of connected client devices.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Projects" /><summary type="html">The aim of this project was to implement an audio server solution which could stream high quality audio across the network to a number of connected client devices.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EE108 - Introduction to Programming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE108.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EE108 - Introduction to Programming" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE108</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE108.html">&lt;p&gt;This module focuses on building software development skills using the C language.
 &lt;!-- more --&gt;
 In particular, the module teaches the students how to approach a problem, to devise a computer-solvable solution, to implement it using C programming language and test it. It then introduces the concepts of functional decomposition (“sub-programs”), parameter passing (by value and by reference), structured data types, pointers, and the facilities of the C standard library. Example application areas include numerical analysis and cryptography.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Undergrad" /><summary type="html">This module focuses on building software development skills using the C language.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EE219 - Object Oriented Programming</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE219.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EE219 - Object Oriented Programming" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE219</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE219.html">&lt;p&gt;This module will equip students with a good working knowledge of object-oriented programming in both the C++ and Java programming languages.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
The module builds on the C programming language skills from first year. By using two different languages students will achieve a good theoretical grounding in general object-oriented programming languages. Students apply their skills through challenging practical assignments.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Undergrad" /><summary type="html">This module will equip students with a good working knowledge of object-oriented programming in both the C++ and Java programming languages.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EE324 - Algorithms</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE324.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EE324 - Algorithms" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE324</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE324.html">&lt;p&gt;The aim of this module is to introduce the student to data structures and algorithms, with an emphasis on applications to engineering problem solving.
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
Students will develop an understanding of a range of abstract data types and fundamental sorting and searching algorithms, and gain practical experience in their implementation using high-level programming languages. Students will also encounter a broad range of applied engineering problem areas, as apply to networks, optimisation and statistical analysis, for example. Students will explore and evaluate different approaches to implementing solutions to engineering problems, given requirements for speed and solution accuracy, or constraints such as real-time response, available processing power, or energy consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Undergrad" /><summary type="html">The aim of this module is to introduce the student to data structures and algorithms, with an emphasis on applications to engineering problem solving.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">EE402 - OOP With Embedded Systems</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE402.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="EE402 - OOP With Embedded Systems" /><published>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-10-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE402</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/undergrad/2019/10/08/EE402.html">&lt;p&gt;Object-oriented Programming is a software methodology that is vital in the engineering workplace. 
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
 This module will allow students to gain further experience in advanced aspects of object-oriented programming through implementation of design concepts in both the C++ and Java programming languages.
 Advanced embedded Linux based embedded systems are introduced in this module. Each student completes an assignment using a system-on-a-chip (SoC) device, such as the BeagleBone that involves TCP socket communications.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Undergrad" /><summary type="html">Object-oriented Programming is a software methodology that is vital in the engineering workplace.</summary></entry></feed>